本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译：小憨加油    王大可   杨一勾  Reginamoon
翻译：feilixiaozi   Charl   某羽  校对：油炸电风扇   杨一勾
时间轴：youliss  今  今天也想弃剧的苏菲
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第十四集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
什么叫你不能接这个案子
What do you mean you can't take the case?
杰西卡不会为工时花钱
Jessica won't lay out the money for the man-hours.
我叔叔基思也是受害者之一
One of the victims was my uncle Keith.
求你了  这些人需要你的帮助
Please. These people need your help.
我没有主动站出来  是他们找到我的
I didn't come forward. They found me.
而且新人的事也不是我搞的
And I'm not pulling any associate shit.
那你怎么解释这份
Then what do you call
候选人名单
this pathetic excuse of a candidates list?
我觉得这是自然而然的  因为我们的学生识字
I call it inevitable, because our students can read.
我们的未来要溜走了  而给杰克命名合伙人地位
Our future is slipping away, and offering Jack
或是跟上帝祈祷哈维
name partner or praying to god that Harvey
能把迈克的案子摆平
just gets Mike off the hook
都没法阻止这事发生
Isn't gonna stop it from happening.
字幕
Then you get your ass back up to Harvard,
你现在就滚去哈佛  确保希拉不会出现在庭审上
And you make sure sheila doesn't show up to that trial.
这是去阿根廷的机票
It's a ticket to Argentina.
我需要你去那儿待到审判结束
I need you to go there until the trial's over.
法庭不听这些废话  那里讲事实
Court's not about bullshit like this; it's about facts.
事实是  你不是律师
And the fact is, you're not a goddamn lawyer.
你是在说我觉得你在说的话吗
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
你要那么想  那你就是蠢货
Because if you're thinking it, you're a fool.
你听到了
You heard her.
她说"事实就是我不是律师"
She said "the fact is, is that I'm not a goddamn lawyer".
那唯一改变那个事实的办法就是
Well, the only way to change that fact
让陪审团看到我是个律师
is for a jury to see me be a goddamn lawyer.
你要那么做  他们看到的就只是
You try that, all they're gonna see
该进监狱的某人
is someone going to prison.
这是我的决定  我要做
It's my call, and I'm making it.
我们有麻烦了  他们找到了特雷弗
We have a problem. They found Trevor.
请举起你的右手
Please raise your right hand.
你愿意发誓
Do you swear to tell the truth,
所言句句属实
the whole truth,
毫不欺瞒
and nothing but the truth,
上帝为证吗
so help you God?
我愿意
I do.
你可以坐下了
You may be seated.
埃文斯先生  你认识罗斯先生多久了
Mr. Evans, how long have you known Mr. Ross?
我们从小就认识  快二十年了
Since we were kids. Almost 20 years.
那你们很亲近吧
So you were close to him?
对  他曾是我最好的朋友
Yeah, he was my best friend.
你现在还跟他很亲近吗
Are you still close to him?
我想在这之后就不会了
Well, I doubt we will be after this.
在什么之后
After what?
在你问我一系列
After you ask me about the series of events
我们今天为之而来的问题之后
that have led us all to be here today.
我们等一下再聊你们之间的历史
Well, we'll get to your history in a minute,
但首先  我想问你一个关于近期事件的问题
But first, I want to ask you a question about current events.
迈克・罗斯有没有在三天前找到你
Did Mike Ross approach you three days ago
企图让你不要上庭指证他
in an attempt to get you not to testify against him?
是的  他来找过我
Yes, he did.
那次对话具体是如何进行的
How exactly did that conversation go?
-你在这里干嘛  -你知道我在这里干嘛
- What are you doing here? - You know exactly what I'm doing here.
你说过你不会出庭作证的
You said you would not testify.
对  但那是在安妮塔・吉布斯把我抓走
Yeah, well, that was before Anita Gibbs dragged me in
告诉我她要把我关十年之前
and told me she was gonna put me away for ten years.
我不在乎她跟你说了什么
I don't give a shit what she told you.
你说过你会叫律师的
You said you were gonna call a lawyer.
对  但我还没机会叫
Yeah, well, before I had a chance to do that,
他们给我看了他们手上的东西
they showed me what they had,
有姓名  日期  证人  以及所有
which is names, dates, witnesses, and everything else
他们需要能把我爱关多久就关多久的东西
they need to put me away for as long as they want.
等等  等等  他们怎么会有
Wait, wait, how would they have--
你以为我愿意这么做吗
You think I want to do this?
我不想的
I don't.
但是我不能为了你冒坐牢的风险
But I cannot risk prison for you.
我向你保证  无论他们掌握了什么
And I am telling you that whatever they have,
哈维都可以为你脱罪的
Harvey can get you out of this.
吉布斯也跟我说了
And from what she told me,
她可以让你脱罪
Gibbs can get you out of this.
她愿意跟你交易  可以让这一切结束
She offered you a deal that can make this whole thing stop.
与其让我不要出庭指证你
Now, instead of telling me not to testify against you,
你为什么不考虑一下指证哈维呢
why don't you think about testifying against Harvey?
因为我不像你  我绝不会背叛朋友
Because unlike you, I would never do that to a friend!
对  但我跟你不一样的是
Yeah, well, unlike you, when they put me away,
他们可不会把我关进白领监狱
I'm not going to a white-collar prison.
所以如果我不出庭作证毁了你
So if I don't rip you to shreds up there on the stand,
他们就会在监狱里毁了我
they're gonna rip me to shreds behind bars.
哈维  很晚了  我今天很累
Harvey, it's late. I've had a long day.
所以如果你不介意的话
So if you don't mind...
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
又怎么了  我家着火了吗
What now? My condo's on fire?
迈克想自己辩护
Mike wants to represent himself.
他疯了吗  他不能那样做
Is he crazy? He can't do that.
我也尝试过告诉他这个
That's what I tried to tell him.
你不该尝试  你应该直接命令他
You don't try; you just tell him.
对  但唯一的问题在于
Yeah, the only problem with that is,
他知道这是他自己的决定
he knows it's his decision.
更别提他没有去找吉布斯
not to mention, the only thing that's stopping him
指证你或者我的唯一原因
from going to Gibbs and pointing his finger
就是他对我们的忠诚
at you or me is his loyalty to us.
那就这么算了吗
So that's it?
就让他为自己辩护
He's representing himself?
我没有这么说
I'm not saying that.
那你到底想说什么
Then what exactly are you saying?
我是说我有个计划
I'm saying I have a plan,
但我需要你的同意
but I need you to sign off on it.
不管是什么计划  我都同意
Oh, whatever it is, I'm in.
因为如果那孩子自己辩护
Because if that kid handles his own defense,
那接下来就是你和我上庭受审了
you and I are going to be the next ones on trial.
如果你来是想知道特雷弗会不会作证  他会
If you're here to find out if Trevor's testifying, he is.
我可以搞定特雷弗
I can handle Trevor.
哈维  我们谈过这个了
Harvey, we've been over this.
我也说过我不会善罢甘休的
And I said we're not done being over it.
我知道老话说自己辩护的律师都是傻瓜
Listen to me, I know that fool-for-a-client bullshit.
但现在他们指控说我不是个律师
But the thing I'm being accused of is not being a lawyer.
所以如果我为自己辩护  那我在庭上的每一秒
So if I represent myself, every second I'm up there,
他们都会看到我就是个律师
they're gonna see me as a lawyer.
但如果她在其中任何一刻打乱你的阵脚
And if she rattles you for one of those goddamn seconds,
他们就会认为你是个骗子
they're gonna see you as a fraud, and they're never
并且再也不会看到你的其他方面
gonna see you as anything else.
好了
Okay.
我知道了  你表达了你的意见
I got it. You said your piece.
这是我的决定  我不想再讨论了
It's my call. I'm done talking about it.
那我们就进行一次模拟庭审来帮你做准备
Then we'll do a trial run to get you ready.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你想浪费我的时间  更别说
You want to waste my time, not to mention
把我们的丑事  向整个公司直播
air our dirty laundry, in front of the whole firm?
迈克  十天之内  我们的丑事
Mike, in a week and a half, our dirty laundry is gonna be
将向全世界直播
aired in front of the whole world.
而且吉布斯会用
And Gibbs is gonna come at you in ways
你意想不到的方式来对付你
you've never even thought about.
我明白了  你不是用模拟庭审来帮我准备
Oh, so I get it. You don't want a trial run to get me ready;
你想用模拟庭审来证明我不是她的对手
you want a trial run to show me that I'm outmatched.
你不是我和吉布斯的对手
You are outmatched by me and Gibbs,
而你害怕承认这个事实
And you're afraid to find out.
我不怕吉布斯  我也不怕你
I'm not afraid of Gibbs, and I am not afraid of you.
那你就不会介意同意  如果我赢了你
Then you won't mind agreeing, if I beat you,
你就让我上庭为你辩护
you let me represent you in court.
好  哈维  你想比一场
Okay, Harvey, you want to go?
那我们就比一场
Let's go.
不过你最好使出浑身解数
But you better bring your A game.
因为你或许确实是全城最好的律师
Because you might be the best closer in the city,
但我是背水一战
But I'm the one fighting for my life.
诉讼双雄
第五季  第十四集
谢谢
Thank you.
找到你了
There he is.
哈罗德
Harold.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我知道发生了什么事  好吗
I know what's going on, okay?
我知道你要面临的庭审
I know about the trial coming up.
那你肯定知道我现在很忙
Then you know I'm pretty busy right now.
对  这也是我找你的原因
Right, which is why I wanted to talk to you.
听着  你会需要有人为你作证
Listen, you're gonna need someone to testify
证明你念过哈佛
that you went to Harvard.
我想为你作证
I want to be that guy.
哈罗德  你的提议很棒  但是
Harold, that's an amazing offer, but--
迈克  拜托  伙计
Mike, come on, man.
我们都知道你没有念过哈佛
We both know that you didn't go to Harvard.
但说实话  如果任何人问过我
But honestly, if anyone would have asked me up until this point,
我都会发誓说你念过
I would have sworn that you did.
我会发誓我看到你出现在
I would have sworn that I saw you
在吉尔克斯的派对上
at that--that party with Gilcrest
或在匹诺曹餐厅吃披萨
or those pizza nights at Pinocchio's
或者在任何一段我当时的记忆里
or pretty much any other memory I have of that time,
也就是说  如果他们让我出庭作证
which means, if they put me up there on that stand,
我基本上是在说实话
I'd basically be telling the truth.
我无法形容这对我多重要  哈罗德  但
I can't tell you how much that means to me, Harold, but...
迈克  我想为你这么做  拜托了
Mike, I want to do this for you, please.
我知道你想
I know you do.
但是我把自己弄到这步田地
But I got myself into this mess,
我得靠自己爬起来
and I got to get myself out of it.
好吧
Okay.
但是  如果你改变主意
But listen, if you change your mind,
你知道应该去哪找我
you know where to find me.
陪审团的女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
你们将在接下来几天
you're gonna be hearing a lot of things
听到很多东西
over the next several days,
但事实上  这个案子
but the truth is, this case is about
证据只有确凿的  无法动摇的
nothing more than cold, hard--
捕风捉影
Innuendo.
而事实是  我可以背诵
And the fact is, I'm capable of reciting every element
纽约州所有的法理学要素
of jurisprudence in the State of New York.
尽管如此  控方将会
and yet despite that, the prosecution is gonna
企图让你们相信我是个
try to convince you that I am a--
骗子  一个没有通过律师考试  也没读过
Fraud, who not only didn't pass the bar or go
法学院的人  他连大学都没毕业
to law school, he didn't even graduate college.
没有任何确凿的证据
There isn't one piece of hard evidence
能证明我没有读过哈佛法学院
proving that I didn't go to Harvard Law.
没有交学费的记录
There's no record of tuition being paid.
没有波士顿地址的记录
No record of a Boston address.
年册里甚至没有一张你的照片
There isn't even a simple picture in the yearbook.
那我们就来聊聊年册
Let's talk about the yearbook.
就像他说的  我没有出现在年册中
As he told you, I'm not in the yearbook.
迈克・罗斯在哪里
Where is Mike Ross?
但他没有告诉你们的是
Though what he didn't tell you is that
还有25个人也没有出现在年册中
25 other students are also not in this yearbook.
那些人有以诈骗罪名被起诉吗
Are those other students being charged with fraud?
当然没有  因为我们不会因为
Of course not, because we don't put people on trial
照相日请病假而被起诉  不论
for being sick on picture day, and no matter--
他怎么说  事实是  迈克・罗斯不是律师
What he says, the fact is, Mike Ross is not a lawyer.
他是个诈骗犯
He's a fraud.
而我们会将此事证明得确凿无疑
And we will prove that beyond a shadow of a doubt.
辩方想传唤第一位证人
The defense would like to call its first witness.
你们看  他多不像个律师
Right there-- he's such a non-lawyer,
他甚至不知道应该是检方先传唤证人
he doesn't even know the prosecution goes first.
那你显然也不知道
And you obviously don't know
1937年贾维斯诉纽约州案
Jarvis V. the State of New York, 1937,
庭审一旦开始
when calling of the first witness
传唤第一位证人的时机
is of such special nature as to disrupt
就是影响庭审连贯性的本质因素
the flow of the trial once it's started.
你说什么本质上呢
What the hell special nature are you talking about?
当辩方的第一位证人
When the defense wants to call the prosecutor
就是该案的检察官时
as its first witness.
哈维  除非你有其他理由推翻这个请求
Harvey, unless you have something to overturn this,
不然请就坐吧
I'm gonna need you to have a seat.
斯佩克特先生  你说我没有
Mr. Specter, you said there's no record of me
在波士顿拥有公寓的证明
ever having an apartment in Boston.
那你能解释一下为什么
Can you explain to the jury why there's no record
你没有住在那里的证明吗
of you ever having lived there?
又不是我受审
I'm not the one on trial here.
确实不是你
No, you're not.
但你坐在证人席上
You're the one in that chair,
还是要请你回答我的问题
so why don't you answer the question,
或者我们就此停止吧
or we can stop this whole thing right now.
我没有住在那里的证明是因为
There's no record of me living there
我在这里有住所所以在那里是跟人分租的
because I sublet up there when I had my place down here.
所以某个人
So it is possible
没有波士顿的住址
that a person not have a Boston address
也不一定意味着他没有在哈佛学习
without it meaning that they didn't attend Harvard.
非常好  谢谢你
Great. Thank you so much.
我问完了
This witness is excused.
那你在那里没有住址
And what, exactly, is your reason
又是什么原因呢
for not having an address up there?
除非你不敢回答我的问题
Unless you're too afraid to answer my questions.
不  我一点也不害怕
No, I'm not afraid of you at all.
我的原因是我选择和我的朋友
My reason is that I chose to live with my friend
特雷弗住在一起
Trevor during that time.
这个说法的唯一问题是
The only problem with that is,
你的朋友特雷弗这辈子都住在布鲁克林区
your friend Trevor has lived in Brooklyn his entire life.
开车三个小时二十分就可以到哈佛
Exactly a 3 hour and 20 minute drive from Harvard.
所以你每天都那样开车往返吗
So you're saying you made that drive every day?
不  我只去参加考试
No, I only went up for tests
因为那样就够了
because that's all I had to do.
看来你还需要一些额外的教导吧
I guess you needed some extra tutoring, huh?
你期望这些人相信你可以
You expect these people to believe that you graduated
一次课都不上还能从全球竞争
from the most competitive law school in the world
最激烈的法学院毕业
without ever going to class?
你看这多可笑  因为你竟然
See, that's funny, because you actually
期待这些人相信
expect these people to believe
我从来没有读过法学院
that I never went to law school at all
但还能不知怎么地
and yet still somehow managed to convince
说服全世界最顶尖的律师们
the smartest lawyers in the world
让我当上了他们最年轻的合伙人
to make me their youngest partner ever.
现在谁的说法看起来更不可信呢
Whose story is looking more far-fetched now?
不回答  很好
Oh, no answer? Great.
我没有问题了  法官大人
No more questions, Your Honor.
我不知道你有没有注意到
I don't know if you've noticed this or not,
但他把你打得屁滚尿流
but he's kicking your ass.
那我就准备回击了
And I'm about to kick back.
你们两个在商量什么
Are you two discussing something
辩方需要知晓的内容吗
that defense should be made aware of?
就是讨论一下体育问题
Just talking about the Knicks.
检方准备好传唤第一位证人了吗
Now is the prosecution ready to call their first witness?
检方的第一位证人是这份
The prosecution's first witness is this affidavit
来自辩方理论上应在班级每位成员的
from every single member of the defendant's
一份宣誓证词
supposed graduating class.
反对  法官大人  我没有看过这份材料
Objection, Your Honor. I haven't seen that.
那我念给你听
Well, then let me read it to you.
我们一起站出来承诺
"We collectively come forward to swear
以下关于迈克尔・詹姆斯・罗斯的信息
the following regarding Michael James Ross:
我们从没见过他  也不认识他
We never saw him. We never knew him.
从没听说过他
We never heard of him.
对于他置哈佛法学院的名声于不顾的行为
And it makes us sick that he's taking the good name
我们也感到异常反感
of Harvard Law School and throwing it down the toilet.
请对所有指控判定有罪
Please find him guilty on all counts."
法官大人  我请求对这份文件立即予以废止
Your honor, I move to strike that document right now.
你的理由是什么
On what grounds?
理由是这是一份伪造的文件
On the grounds that it's completely fabricated.
你的证据呢
Where's your proof?
我们先不谈我确实在哈佛就读过这个事实
Besides the fact that I actually went to Harvard,
你根本不可能从昨晚到现在
there's no way you could have contacted
联系到全部的人
all of those people since last night.
那我建议你联系他们所有人
Then I suggest you call every one of these people
让他们来出庭作证
and put them on the stand.
但当你那么做的时候  他们每个人
But when you do, every single one of them is gonna
都会看着你的眼睛问  "你是谁啊"
look you in the eye and say, "Who the hell are you?"
怎么了  怎么不出声了
What? No snappy comeback?
你可以尽你所能愚弄这些人
You can try to trick these people all you want.
但事实就是你没有读过哈佛
But the fact is, you didn't go to Harvard,
这也证明了这件事
and this proves it.
反对  他在作证
Objection. He's testifying.
我只是在赢而已
What I'm doing is winning.
好了  够了
All right, that's enough.
我认为我们该休息一下了
I think this is a good time to take a break.
路易・利特
Louis Litt.
我是安妮塔・吉布斯
I'm Anita Gibbs.
我知道你是谁
Yeah, I know who you are.
问题是你在这里干什么
Question is, what are you doing here?
答案是  你说什么我也不在乎
And the answer is, I don't give a shit.
我是来夸奖你
I came here to compliment you
摆脱希拉・赛斯的方式的
on getting rid of Sheila Sazs.
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
真的吗  你以为我不知道发生了什么吗
Really? You think I don't know what's going on here?
你们两个曾经交往过  但当你发现
You two were in a relationship, and when you found out
是她写的那封邮件时
that it was her that wrote that email,
你去了剑桥说服她
you went up to Cambridge and convinced her to go to
在庭审期间去了阿根廷
Argentina for the duration of the trial.
你简直是疯了
You're out of your mind.
是吗
Am I?
你过去两周飞去波士顿三次
You flew to Boston three times in the last two weeks.
你搭车去过两次她家
You took two cabs to her house
还有一次离招生办公室100英尺都不到
and another to within 100 feet of the admissions office.
你没有任何证据
You have no proof of anything.
我不需要证据
I don't need proof.
因为尽管她现在在阿根廷
Because while she may be in Argentina now,
但她不会永远呆在那里
she's not gonna stay there forever,
也就是说等她回来的时候
which means when she gets back,
我就能证明你在骚扰证人
I get you for witness tampering.
拜托你离我远点
Do me a favor and leave me the hell alone.
我会的
I will.
暂时而已
For now.
如果她在庭审前没有回来
But if she's not back by the start of trial,
我会认为你想被起诉
I'm gonna assume that you want to be brought up on charges.
你这个混蛋  这不是真的
You son of a bitch. This isn't real.
我不在乎那是不是真的
I don't give a shit whether it's real or not.
你认为吉布斯不会那么做吗
You think Gibbs isn't gonna do things like that?
但她不会作伪证的  你也知道
She is not gonna enter false evidence, and you know it.
但她会为你设下陷阱
But she is gonna set up traps for you
就像我刚才那样
to bungle into like I just did.
那是胡说八道
This is such bullshit.
你生气是因为你输得很惨
You are just pissed because I was kicking your ass
然后你就想作弊
so now you're cheating.
我
Me?
是你想抓住一切机会
You're the one who testified in your
进行公开陈述
opening statement and every chance you get.
因为那是为自己辩护所必须的结果
Because that's exactly what me being my own lawyer gives us.
我不在乎
I don't care.
假如我代理你  结果需要你作证
If I represent you and it turns out that you need to testify,
我们可以传唤你上证人席
we can call you up to the stand.
假如我们那样做了
And if we do that,
那吉布斯就可以盘问我
then Gibbs gets to cross-examine me
并且让我看起来像个骗子
and make me look like a liar.
我不知道你注意到没有
Well, I don't know if you've noticed,
你看起来已经像个骗子了
but you're looking like a liar right now.
而我在试图让你看起来不像个傻瓜
And I'm trying to keep you from looking like a fool.
知道吗  我有点烦你不断喊我傻瓜了
You know what? I'm getting pretty tired of you using that word with me.
那太糟了  因为尽管你说了那一大通话
Too bad, because for all your bullshit up there,
你仍然无法提供一个记得你上过哈佛的人
you still can't produce one person who remembers you from Harvard.
所以假如你想有机会代理你自己
So if you want to have a chance at representing yourself,
那就快从我面前滚开  去想你的辩护词
get out of my face and go work on your defense
因为我的后招还有很多
'cause I got a lot more where that came from.
有什么我能为你效劳  路易
What can I do for you, Louis?
-吉布斯知道我的所作所为了  -什么
- Gibbs knows what I did. - What?
她知道我让希拉出了国
She knows I got Sheila out of the country.
她今早在门口等着我
She was waiting for me this morning,
并且威胁要起诉我
and she threatened to bring charges against me.
-你承认了吗  -没有
- Did you admit that to her? - No.
那她就无法起诉你任何事
Then she's not gonna charge you with anything.
你听见我刚刚说的了吗
Did you hear what I just said?
她知道了我在希拉去阿根廷的那晚
She knows I went to Sheila's place
去了她家
the same night she went to Argentina.
那又能证明什么
And what does that prove?
这证明了我有意
It proves that I knowingly
在一场调查正在进行中时
bought a witness a ticket out of the country
给一名证人买了张出国机票
in the middle of an ongoing investigation.
那一切只能证明  你奖励了一位
All it proves is, you rewarded a Harvard employee
在过去十年中一直向这家律所输送律师的
who's been steering lawyers towards this firm
哈佛职员
for the last ten years.
杰西卡  吉布斯可以轻易到阿根廷去
Okay, Jessica, Gibbs can easily go down to Argentina
然后问希拉
and ask Sheila--
路易  听听你自己说的话
Louis, listen to yourself.
她不会那样做的
She's not going to do that.
而且就算她那样做了
And even if she did,
在证人没有被传唤的情况下
it's not witness tampering
那也不算干扰证人
if a subpoena was never issued.
那吉布斯就会说我知道
Then Gibbs is gonna say that I had knowledge
有张即将到来的传票  因此就是干扰
of an impending subpoena; therefore it is tampering.
你知道吗  路易
You know what, Louis?
我一点都不在乎吉布斯怎么说
I don't give a shit what Gibbs says.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
让那个女人自食她所造的苦果
Give that woman a taste of her own goddamn medicine.
你要去哪里
Where the hell are you going?
我们套住迈克了
We've got Mike on the ropes;
我们得让他别插手这事
we have to put him away.
抱歉  哈维
Sorry, Harvey.
刚刚出现了件更紧急的事
Something more pressing just came up.
还能有什么比这更紧急
What the hell could be more pressing than this?
你操心你自己的事  让我自己操心我的
You worry about your shit, and I'll worry about mine.
我已经把我的事搞定了
Oh, I've got my shit taken care of.
也许你搞定了  也许你没搞定
Well, maybe you do, and maybe you don't.
反正我近来学到的是
But what I've learned from recent history is,
假如你真的是安妮塔・吉布斯
if you really were Anita Gibbs,
不管你计划了什么
no matter what you had planned,
你其实都是另有打算
you'd be planning something else.
唐娜  拜托  现在不是时候
Donna, please, not right now.
我忙死了
I'm so busy.
没关系
That's fine.
我只是过来告诉你一声
I just came by to let you know that
杰西卡得出趟门
Jessica had to go out,
所以今天不继续举行模拟庭审了
so the trial is done for the rest of the day.
而哈维不打算告诉我
And Harvey wasn't gonna tell me
因为他在玩阴的
because he's playing dirty.
他不是你的敌人  迈克
He's not your enemy, Mike.
他只是在做他认为最好的
He's just doing what he thinks is best.
那我要做我认为最好的
Then I'm gonna do what I think is best.
那你认为怎么最好
And what exactly is that?
听着  唐娜  他或许不是我的敌人
Look, Donna, he may not be my enemy,
你或许也不是我的敌人
and you may not be my enemy,
但只要我们在模拟庭审中
but as long as we're in this trial run,
我是绝对不会信任你的
I'm not trusting you with anything.
果然是好孩子
That's my boy.
杰西卡・皮尔逊
Jessica Pearson,
我不知道我们今天约了见面
I wasn't aware we had an appointment today.
我们没约
We don't.
我只是过来给你这个限制令
I just stopped by to give you this restraining order,
阻止你在路易・利特的律师不在场的情况下
preventing you from contacting Louis Litt
接触他
without his attorney present.
让我猜猜...他的律师是你
And let me guess-- his attorney is you.
猜对了
Bingo.
所以除非你要逮捕他
So unless you're going to arrest him,
否则哪怕你只是发发短信  只要我不在场
you so much as text him without me present,
你也是违反了法院命令
and you're in violation of a court order.
你休想再继续挑拨我和我的人了
You're done driving a wedge between me and my people.
当我把你手下所有人一个个拉上证人席
We'll see how strong your bond is with your people
并直截了当地问他们
when I parade every one of them on the stand
"你知道迈克・罗斯是个骗子吗"
and ask them point-blank,
我们就能看到你和你的人联系是有多紧密了
"Did you know Mike Ross was a fraud?"
你觉得我们对那个问题会有不同的答案吗
You think we're gonna have different answers to that?
不  我觉得你们都会引用第五修正案
No, I think you're all gonna take the Fifth.
然后你们会自我安慰那样并不会显得心虚
And you're gonna tell yourselves it implies no guilt,
但在陪审团的眼里
but in the eyes of the jury,
你们可都相当于站在那里说出他的确有罪了
you might as well all just stand up there and say he did it.
所以你告诉你的客户我暂时不会找他麻烦了
So you tell your client he's off the hook for now.
但下次我再找他谈
But the next time I talk to him,
将会是他站在证人席上时
it will be on the stand.
我收到你的信息了
Hey, I got your message.
所以我来了
So here I am.
但我就直说了  迈克
But let me tell you something, Mike,
假如你的来意和我想象中的一样
if you're here to ask what I think you're gonna ask,
那我俩没啥好谈的
gonna be a short conversation.
我需要你说你记得我上过哈佛
I need you to say you remember me from Harvard.
只有一个小问题  迈克
There's just one small problem, Mike.
我不记得你
I don't remember you.
因为你没上过哈佛  不是吗
'Cause you didn't go there, did you?
看着我的眼睛  告诉我我说错了
Look me in the eye and tell me that I'm wrong.
该死的  迈克  我就知道
God damn you, Mike. I--I knew it.
吉米  吉米
Jimmy--Jimmy!
在我们刚开始工作时
When we first started,
你求我帮你保住你的饭碗
you begged me to help you save your career.
不不不不  迈克  这两件事可不一样
No, no, no, no, Mike. This is not the same thing.
我本可以让你丢掉律师资格的
I-I could have gotten you disbarred.
但那不会让我进监狱  而你清楚这一点
But it couldn't have got me sent to jail, and you know it.
我不在乎
I don't care! All right?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
迈克  你在要求我作伪证
Mike, you are asking me to perjure myself,
而我甚至不了解你到底是个怎样的人
and I don't even know who you are.
不  你了解
Yes, you do.
我就是在你婶婶需要帮助时你求助的那个人
I am the same guy you came to when your aunt needed help.
怎么  那次也算我欠你的吗
What? So I owe you for that too?
没错
Yeah, you do.
你我都清楚假如我被定罪了
You and I both know if I get convicted,
那个和解协议就会被重新审理
that settlement's gonna get reopened.
那你当时到底为什么要接受那个协议  迈克
Then why the hell did you take it, Mike?
为什么
Why?
吉米  我当时走了捷径
Jimmy, I took a shortcut, man.
就和你曾经也走过捷径一样
Just like you took a shortcut once.
假如我能收回一切  我会的
Now, if I could take it all back, I would,
但我做不到
but I can't.
就和你曾经求过我一样
And just like you begged me once,
我现在来找你  来求你
I am coming to you and begging you right now.
拜托了
Please.
求你帮帮我
Please help me.
没有一个脑子正常的人
No one in their right mind
会答应你求我做的事
would do what you're asking me to.
并非如此
That's not true.
-哈罗德去找你了吗  -没错
- Harold come to you? - Mm-hmm.
但你知道哈罗德
But you know Harold
在证人席上是撑不住的  但我可以
won't hold up on the stand and I would.
是不是
Right?
-吉米  我需要你...  -迈克
- Jimmy, I need you-- - Michael.
听着  兄弟  我很抱歉
Look, brother, I'm sorry.
我真的很希望自己能帮你
I really wish I could help,
但我不能为你而冒进监狱的风险
but I cannot risk going to prison for you.
我做不到
I can't.
喂
Hello?
路易  是我
Louis, it's me.
希拉  我明确告诉过你
Sheila, I explicitly told you,
"在打完官司前不要打电话给我"
"Do not call me until after the trial is over."
我们不能冒任何险...
We can't take any chances--
有人找到我了  路易
Someone approached me, Louis.
什么叫有人找到你了
What do you mean someone approached you?
就在我住的酒店
At my hotel.
我当时在大堂
I was in the lobby.
一个男人上来和我说话
A man came up to me and started talking.
他说是从纽约来的
He said he was from New York.
想知道我计划去阿根廷旅行
He wanted to know how long I'd been
计划多久了
planning a trip to Argentina.
还问我打算待多久
Then he asked how long I was planning on staying
最后还问我
and, finally, did anyone pay
是否有人出钱让我来这儿
for my ticket to come down here?
那你是怎么回答他的
W-what did you tell him?
我说那不关他的事
That it was none of his business.
很好  很聪明
Good. That was smart.
不能让他们觉得已经把你握在手心了
You didn't show them that they got to you.
路易  他们已经把我握在手心了
Louis, they did get to me.
听我说
Listen to me.
他们没传唤你  所以你没做错什么
They did not subpoena you, so you did nothing wrong.
你只是旅个行而已
You just took a trip.
就算吉布斯能咬定谁做了什么  那也是我
Now, if Gibbs can prove anyone did anything, it is me.
我会不惜一切保护你的
And I will do anything to protect you, okay?
对不起  路易  我得挂了
I'm sorry, Louis. I have to go.
难以置信
I don't believe you.
你居然让瑞秋当第一个证人
You're calling Rachel as your first witness?
没错
I sure as hell am.
吉布斯传唤不了瑞秋  我们已经搞定这个了
Gibbs can't call Rachel. We took care of that.
我们只让她没办法耍手段
We took care of her going out of bounds
让瑞秋指认你
to get Rachel to turn on you.
没让她不能传唤瑞秋
We didn't do anything to stop her calling Rachel
出庭作证  你心里清楚
to the stand, and you know it.
那我现在郑重声明
Fine, then I'm stipulating right now
对所有问题  瑞秋都引用第五修正案
Rachel's taking the fifth to any questions.
胡说
Oh, bullshit.
我们都知道
You know as well as I do,
私人问题上她没办法引用第五修正案
she can't take the fifth to personal questions.
所以你为了吓唬我
So you're just gonna humiliate her
就要羞辱她吗
so you can rattle me?
你说对了
You're damn right I am.
吉布斯也会做同样的事
Gibbs is gonna do the exact same thing.
她不会再陪审团面前
She is not gonna do that to Rachel
羞辱瑞秋  因为那会让她自贬身价
in front of a jury, because it will make her look like shit.
她可不关心自己的身价
She doesn't care about that.
不  不关心的人是你
No, you're the one that doesn't care about that.
因为这已经不是为我的案子着想了
'Cause this is no longer about what's best for my case;
你是单纯的不想输给我
it's because you don't want to lose to me.
我不会输给你
I'm not going to lose to you.
你知道吗  哈维  我...
You know what, Harvey? I am--
别吵了
That's enough.
你们俩在这儿吵个没完的时候
While you two have been having your pissing contest,
我一直在翻旧文件
I've been poring over discovery,
我发现了迈克大一的班级排名
and I came across the class rankings from Mike's first year.
别告诉我上面没有他
Don't tell me-- he's not on it.
-确实没有  -这说不通
- No, he's not. - Doesn't make any sense.
说得通
Yes, it does.
罗拉没改完所有文件
Lola must not have covered all the bases.
那我们得让她都改完
Then we need to get her to cover all the bases.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
你去找罗拉  就把吉布斯引过去了
You go to Lola, you lead Gibbs right to her,
这件事还没来得及开始就会结束
and this thing is over before it even gets started.
那我们让本杰明改
Okay, then we get Benjamin to do it.
不能再让别人知道你的秘密了
We are not letting another person in on your secret.
那你觉得我们该怎么办
Well, then what do you suggest we do?
我们要搞定所有让我们
What we were gonna do with every other piece
看起来有罪的证据
of evidence that makes us look like shit.
让那些证据不堪一击
We find a way to make it look like shit.
哈佛不可能碰巧忘了
There is no way that Harvard accidentally forgets
给一个学生排名
to put a student on this list.
要我说就去找本杰明
I say we go to Benjamin.
你要是再提这个
And I say I'll lock you in a room
我就把你锁进小黑屋直到开庭
until this trial starts if you say that again.
看来只能胜者做决定了
Then I guess whoever wins makes the call.
要是还没分出胜负你就背着我去找本杰明
You go to Benjamin behind my back before we're done,
那坐牢都算
and you going to prison is gonna be
便宜你了
the least of your problems.
迈克  你怎么像被痛扁了一顿似的
Mike, you like you've been through the wringer.
我得问你个问题
I have to ask you a question, and...
希望你诚实回答我
I want you to tell me the truth.
你问吧
Well, of course.
你觉得我是该自己为自己辩护
Do you really think I should be the one up there
还是让哈维为我辩护
fighting for my life, or do you think Harvey should be?
我觉得
I think that...
只有你能做这个决定
You're the best person to make that call,
无论你怎么决定  我都完全支持
And that whatever you decide, I'm with you 100%.
那我得拜托本杰明为我们做件事
Well, then I need to ask Benjamin to do something for us,
哈维肯定相当不满
and Harvey is really not gonna like it.
不管什么事  只要你认为有必要
Whatever it is, if you think we need to do it,
我就支持你
I'm with you.
哈佛大学毕业证书
迈克尔・詹姆斯・罗斯
已经搞定了
It's done?
是的
Yes.
管不了一世  但顶得了一时
It won't hold up forever, but it will hold up for now.
谢谢  本杰明
Thank you, Benjamin. I--
我没想到这么快
I didn't expect it for a couple of hours.
都没来得及给你弄点吃的
I-I haven't had a chance to get you any bacon.
没关系  迈克尔
That's quite all right, Michael.
这次算我请你
This one is on the house.
你从没问过我
You know, you never asked if what
那些流言是不是真的
they're saying about me is true.
用不着问
I didn't need to.
我一听就知道是真的
I knew it was true the second I heard it.
我不明白
I don't understand.
念过哈佛的那些孩子
All these kids who went to Harvard,
他们从不在意我
They never gave me the time of day.
他们只想让我知道
All they cared about was letting me know
他们念过而我没念过的大学
where they went to school and I didn't.
你从没这么对我
You've never done that to me.
一次都没有
Not one time.
我不知道该说什么
I--I don't know what to say.
就说等你搞定这件事之后
Say that when you're done and you've beaten this thing,
你不会开始像那些念过哈佛的人一样混蛋
You won't start acting like some asshole who went to harvard.
这个真没法保证  本杰明
Well, I mean, can't really promise you that, Benjamin.
我就要念过哈佛了
I'll have gone to Harvard.
一点不好笑  迈克尔
That's not funny, Michael.
检方准备好传唤下一位证人了吗
Is the prosecution ready to call its next witness?
检方传唤瑞秋・赞恩
Prosecution calls Rachel Zane.
反对
Objection.
法官大人  证人不能因为要引用第五修正案
Your Honor, the witness cannot object to testifying
就随便拒绝作证
simply because she intends to take the fifth.
证人不需要作证是因为她是我的妻子
The witness doesn't have to testify because she's my wife.
什么
What?
我这里有份内华达州的
I have a marriage certificate here
结婚证明能表明
from the state of Nevada showing that
证人和我在交往六周后
the witness and I were married in Las Vegas
就在拉斯维加斯结婚了
six weeks after we started dating.
你们俩都过来
Both of you up here, now.
你到底从哪儿弄来的证明
Where the hell did you get that?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你明知道你没娶她
You didn't marry her, and you know it.
那我怎么会有娶了她的证明
Then why do I have everything I need proving I did?
因为你耍了手段
Because you did some bullshit to get out of this.
看看谁要哭了
Oh, look who's crying about it now.
你们都小点声
Keep your voices down.
你当这是玩笑吗
You think this is a joke?
你要是在法庭上用这招
You try this in court,
吉布斯会证明你没结婚
Gibbs is gonna prove you're not married,
瑞秋就要因伪造罪坐牢了
and Rachel's gonna go to jail for perjury.
他说的没错  你最好清楚自己在做什么
He's right; you better know what the hell you're doing.
谁说我要在真正的法庭上用这个了
Who said that I was gonna use this in the real trial?
我懂了  这是假的  就像你一样
I get it. This is a fake, just like you.
我让你小点声
I said keep your goddamn voice down.
这份证明和那份证词一样真
This is as real as that affidavit was, okay?
你想打败我吗  我现在已经打败你了
Now, you wanted to rattle me; I've rattled you.
你能怎么办
What are you gonna do about it?
检方传唤瑞秋・赞恩作证
Prosecution calls Rachel Zane to the stand.
反对  我们刚已经说清楚了
Objection. We just went over this.
当涉及配偶特权时
When spousal privilege is invoked in the moment,
检方有权挑战
prosecution has the right to challenge
这段婚姻的真实性
the validity of the marriage.
-这真是荒唐  -反对无效
- This is ridiculous. - Objection overruled.
赞恩小姐  请出庭作证
Ms. Zane, take the stand.
我们可以跳过让她宣誓那部分
We can skip swearing her in
反正她也不会说真话
since she's just gonna lie about it, anyway.
反对
Objection!
赞恩小姐  若你和被告在约会六周后就结婚了
Ms. Zane, if you got married six weeks after dating the defendant,
为什么现在又和他订婚了呢
why are you engaged to him right now?
那时候只是一时兴起
Because we did it on a whim.
而且我们也打算要撤销的
And we had planned to have an annulment,
但后来我们越来越相爱  我们觉得
but once we fell more in love, we thought that it
或许等再结婚了再告诉家人们
might be wonderful to reveal it to our families
也是个不错的主意
after we were married again.
那你们第一次结婚的时候
And how, exactly, did it go
具体是个什么情形呢
when you got married the first time?
我们当时是在拉斯维加斯
We were in Las Vegas--
我没兴趣知道你们在哪里
Yeah, yeah, I don't give a shit where you were.
你的婚纱是什么颜色的  蛋糕又是什么颜色的
What color was your dress? What color was the cake?
-反对  -当时有谁在场
- Objection. - Who was there?
-有任何证人吗  -法官大人  他骚扰证人
- Were there any witnesses? - Your Honor, he's badgering--
都有谁看到了  而且具体是几点
Who were the witnesses? And what goddamn time was it?
法官大人  让他下来
Your honor, get him off of her!
-哈维  -现在就告诉我
- Harvey... - Tell me right now.
让证人先回答
Let the witness answer.
婚纱是白色的
The dress was white.
蛋糕是香草味的  上面撒着奶油糖霜
And the cake was vanilla with a buttercream frosting.
典礼很小  大概在晚上10点左右
It was a small ceremony at around 10:00 p.m.
我还记得那个为我们证婚的人
And I remember the man who married us
一切都如昨日般清晰
like it was yesterday
因为那是我一生中最特别的一天
because it was the most special day of my life.
那当你编这个故事的时候
And when you came up with this story,
罗斯先生有没有至少给你自由发挥的权利
did Mr. Ross at least give you the courtesy of
让你自己编你那所谓的神圣的一天
letting you make up your own memories of your supposedly sacred day?
反对
Objection.
既然  他选择在庭审中自己打辩护
Since, if he represents himself at trial,
你可能在未来的两到五年里都不会有婚礼了
you won't have a real wedding for at least two to five years.
哈维
Harvey.
我还有一个问题
And I've got one more question:
你有没有发誓在整段婚姻中
Did you vow to remain faithful to Mr. Ross
都对罗斯先生忠贞不渝
throughout your marriage?
是的  我说过
Yes, I did.
那我猜当你背着他跟洛根・桑德斯
Yeah, then I guess when you cheated on him
偷情的时候  就说明你在那个
with Logan Sanders, it means you lied to him
根本不存在的典礼上说的是假话
at that non-existent ceremony,
就像你现在在骗我们一样
just like you're lying to all of us right now.
够了
That's enough.
如果你想用更多的无关消息
If you want to bring more outside information
来反驳这桩婚事的话  请自便  但现在
to dispute this marriage, feel free, but for right now...
证人可以离席了
this witness is excused.
路易  不管什么事  等下再说
Louis, whatever it is, it's going to have to wait.
不行  等不了了
No, it's not gonna wait,
因为你说过你会搞定吉布斯的
because you said you'd take care of Gibbs.
我的确有搞定吉布斯啊
I did take care of Gibbs.
那为什么她办公室里有人
Well, then why the hell did someone from her office
联系了身在阿根廷的希拉
contact Sheila in Argentina?
路易  他们只是在吓唬你罢了
Louis, they're just trying to scare you.
而且就算她和盘托出
And even if she tells them everything,
你也没做错什么
you did nothing wrong with Sheila.
那迈克的事呢
What about what we did with Mike?
他们唯一能证明我们知道迈克的事的证据
The only proof they'll ever have that we knew about mike
就是我们自己亲口承认
is if we tell them.
如果他们问到我  我就引用第五修正案
And when they ask me, I'm going to take the Fifth,
你也是如此
and you are going to do the same thing.
这还不够好
That is not good enough.
我不想引用第五修正案
I don't want to take the Fifth.
-你说什么  -你听到了的
- Excuse me? - You heard me.
你先被传唤  你先上庭
You get called first, you get up there,
你看着他们的眼睛
and you look them straight in the eye,
你告诉他们迈克上了哈佛
and you tell them Mike went to Harvard.
是你决定雇的他
It was your decision to hire him,
而且你绝对坚持这个决定
and you stand by it 100%.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
事情就是杰西卡让我干扰证人时
What's going on is that Jessica's happy asking me
倒是很轻松  轮到她自己上庭了
to witness tamper, but when it comes to her
她倒不
getting on the stand, she won't--
干扰证人  你让他干什么了
Witness tamper? What did you have him do?
她让我把希拉弄出国去
She had me move Sheila out of the country.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
我只是做了我必须做的事
Look, I did what I had to do.
那你怎么不为我做点必须做的事
Then why won't you do what you have to do for me?
因为如果我做了  那我就有作伪证之嫌了
Because if I did that, it would open me up to perjury.
如果迈克真的被判有罪
If Mike gets convicted,
你作个伪证又有什么关系
what does it matter if you perjure yourself?
都给我闭嘴
Both of you be quiet.
看看谁来了
Look who's coming.
看看都是谁啊  三个火枪手啊
Look who it is. The Three Musketeers.
我们正在开会
And we happen to be in the middle of a meeting.
没关系  我只是来提醒一下
That's okay; I just dropped by to let you know
好像庭审被提前到明天了
it looks like the trial's been moved up till tomorrow.
你干了什么
What the hell did you do?
我去找了法官  我说  法官大人
I went to the judge, and I said, "Your Honor,
我想在我仅有的证人都消失前
"I'd like to start this thing before
开始这场庭审
every single witness I have disappears."
没有我们在场她是不可能同意的
No way she granted this without us present.
你可以争取一下  如果你想的话
Oh, you can fight it, if you want.
我们可以等到赛斯女士旅游完回来
We'll wait for Ms. Sazs to finish her trip.
对此利特先生看起来很不安呢
Oh, Mr. Litt seems upset about that.
看来我对你们使的离间计
Looks like the wedge I'm driving between you
开始起作用了
is starting to work.
你的离间计屁用没有
Your wedge hasn't done shit.
我再告诉你一件事
And I'm gonna tell you something else.
你让我上庭
You put me on that stand,
我就看着陪审团的眼睛
and I will look the jury straight in the eye
明明白白地告诉他们迈克・罗斯是
and tell them that Mike Ross is the best
我遇到过哈佛教出的最好的律师
goddamn Harvard-educated attorney I have ever met.
是我雇了他
I hired him.
是我的决定  而且我绝对坚持该决定
It was my decision, and I stand by it 100%.
而我之后的每个人
And everyone that comes after me
都会说一样的话
will say the same thing.
你觉得她吃你这一套吗
You think she bought that?
管她吃不吃呢
I don't care if she bought it or not.
我不是虚张声势
I wasn't bluffing.
你和迈克最好想想
And you and Mike better figure out
到底该怎么做
what the hell you're going to do
因为明天就开庭了
because the trial starts tomorrow.
一周在这儿碰到你两次
What a coincidence running into you here
真巧啊
twice in one week.
鼓励就算了
You can skip trying to cheer me up,
反正也不管用
because it's not gonna work.
-瑞秋  -我不想听
- Rachel-- - I don't want to hear it.
他在整个律所的人面前羞辱我
He humiliated me in front of the entire firm.
是的
Yeah, he did.
但你不能确定迈克能不能撑得住
But you weren't sure if Mike could handle this or not.
至少现在  如果他真不行
And at least now, if he can't,
你可以不做那个去告诉他此事的恶人
you won't have to be the one to tell him.
这话你说起来容易  因为你根本不知道
That is so easy for you to say, because you have no idea
经历这一切是什么样的感受
what it felt like to go through that.
你错了
You're wrong.
我确确实实地知道那是什么感觉
I know exactly what it feels like.
你是指什么
What are you talking about?
想象一下当我弃他投奔路易时他是怎么对我的
Try to imagine how he treated me when I left him for Louis.
或许你真的懂
Maybe you do know.
是的  我懂
Yeah. I do.
而且
And...
我还知道  无人能及地
I also know that, like nobody else,
哈维有这个能力
Harvey has this ability
屏蔽一切  不再把你当人看
to just shut off and not see you as a person anymore.
这能力真是让我郁闷
Well, that ability makes me sick.
这可能也是他成功的
It's also probably one of the things
因素之一吧
that makes him such a great lawyer.
-你来干什么  -我们有麻烦了
- What are you doing here? - We got a problem.
你是说除了你今天的行为吗
You mean besides what you did today?
-迈克  听我说  -不  你听我说
- Mike, listen to me. - No, you listen to me.
-那真的是太过分了  -明天开庭
- That was over the line-- - The trial starts tomorrow.
什么
What?
不  吉布斯做不到的
No. Gibbs can't do that.
严格来说她的确不行
Technically she can't,
但相信我  我们也没有站得住脚的理由反对
But trust me, we don't have a leg to stand on.
好吧
Fine.
那我就提交申请由我自行辩护
Then I'm filing the motion to be my own attorney.
-迈克  -我不想听
- Mike--no. - I don't want to hear it.
你没有打败我  好吗
You didn't beat me, all right?
你可以作第二辩护人或不为我辩护  但我要当首席辩护人
So you can be second chair or no chair, but I am first chair.
该死的  迈克
God damn it, Mike.
你不知道你在干什么
You don't know what you're doing.
在你对瑞秋痛下狠手之后
Do you really think I'm gonna let you
你真的以为我会让你来保护我吗
protect me after what you did to Rachel today?
我对瑞秋毫不留情全是为了你
I did that to Rachel for you,
如果你连这都看不透  你不能赢这场庭审
and if you can't see that, you can't win this trial.
我能  而且我会
I can, and I will!
够了
That's enough!
瑞秋  没事儿  我能解决这事儿
Rachel, it's fine. I can handle this.
我不在乎   我不想让你来处理此事
I don't care. I don't want you to handle this.
什么
What?
你说过你百分之百支持我
You said you were with me 100%.
那是谎话吗
Was that a lie?
不是  只是哈维今天对我做的一切太残忍
No, but what Harvey had to do to me today was brutal,
不管最终由谁为你辩护
and whoever ends up representing you has to do
都会对特雷弗做相同的事
the same thing to Trevor.
你觉得我不能对特雷弗做出相同的事吗
You don't think I can do the same thing to Trevor?
我知道你能
I know you can.
但是当哈维质证我时  我很讨厌他
But I hated Harvey while he was doing it to me,
而你质证特雷弗时
and they're going to hate you
他们也会讨厌你
while you're doing it to Trevor.
而且  迈克  我们不能让陪审团讨厌你
And, Mike, we can't have the jury hating you,
但是我们可以让他们讨厌哈维
but we can let them hate Harvey.
埃文斯先生  在罗斯先生声称他就读于哈佛大学期间
Mr. Evans, is it true that you were living with Mr. Ross
你确实跟他住在一起是吗
in and around the time he claims to have attended Harvard?
没错  我们共住一间公寓
Yes, we shared an apartment
地址是布鲁克林区亨廷顿达到5307号
at 5307 Huntington Boulevard in Brooklyn.
他是如何支付他的房租呢
And how exactly did he pay his rent?
他找了一份邮递员的差事  然后又做了一份兼职
He worked as a bike messenger and made money on the side
专替别人参加法学院入学考试
taking the LSATs for people.
等一下  我有点糊涂了
Oh, wait, I'm confused.
他为何要依靠那种手段谋生
Why would he have to resort to that
如果他是一名大学毕业生
if he were a college graduate?
因为他不是大学生毕业生
Because he wasn't a college graduate.
什么
What?
你是说他没有从大学毕业吗
You mean he never graduated from college?
对  他因为考试作弊而被学校开除
No, he was kicked out of college for cheating on a test.
这样啊  那有没有可能
Well, isn't it possible
在你和他住在一起时
that while he was living with you,
他又回到了学校  然后完成了他的学业
he went back to school and completed his degree?
罗尔斯法官
我不知道他怎么办到那点  因为他的大部分空闲时间
Well, I don't see how, since most of his spare time
都花在和我一起吸大麻上
was spent sitting around smoking weed with me.
让我来理理思路
Well, let me get this straight.
在他被皮尔逊-斯佩克特雇佣之前
Before he was employed at Pearson Specter,
你所清楚知道的是  他从事了一份
to the best of your knowledge, he worked as
邮递员的工作  还兼职替他人参加法学院入学考试
a bike messenger and a part-time LSAT imposter?
没错
Yes.
最后一个问题  埃文斯先生
One last question, Mr. Evans.
有没有一丝可能迈克・罗斯
Is it at all possible that Mike Ross
曾经在哈佛大学法学院上过学
ever attended Harvard law school?
除非他们在布鲁克林区亨廷顿大道5307号
Not unless they had a satellite campus at
建了分校
5307 Huntington Boulevard in Brooklyn.
问题问完了  法官大人
No more questions, your honor.
由于你吸食大麻  埃文斯先生
Given that you smoked all this pot, Mr. Evans,
有没有可能迈克・罗斯一周一次
isn't it possible that if Mike Ross commuted one day
前往哈佛大学法学院读书  而你又不记得那天
a week to Harvard law that you might not remember that?
我记得
I'd remember.
没错  或许你记得  但是不管怎样
Yeah, maybe you would, but you'd lie
你都会对那件事撒谎  对吗
through your teeth about it anyway, wouldn't you?
反对
Objection.
埃文斯先生  你是不是一名长期的毒品贩子
Mr. Evans, isn't it true that you're a long-time
而你今天之所以会在此作证
drug dealer and your testimony today is only happening
全是因为你和吉布斯达成协议  她会给你豁免权
because you signed a deal with Ms. Gibbs giving you immunity?
那也不表示我在撒谎
Doesn't mean I'm lying.
你不会撒谎
Because you wouldn't lie
是因为你不想进监狱吗
just to get out of going to prison?
对  我不会
No, I would not.
那你觉得另外一个理由怎么样
Well, how about if the other reason was to get back
你这样做是为了报复你这辈子都嫉妒的人
at someone you've been jealous of your entire life?
我这辈子从未嫉妒过迈克・罗斯
I've never been jealous of Mike Ross in my entire life.
我正好发现你在撒谎
And I just caught you in a lie.
反对  法官大人
Objection, your honor.
埃文斯先生  我下一步将要传唤
Mr. Evans, my next move is gonna be to call
珍妮・格里菲思出庭
Jenny Griffith to the stand,
她将会证实你关于毒品交易一事
and she's gonna testify that you lied to her for years
对她撒了数年的谎  当她发现时
about dealing, and when she found out about it,
她离开了你  和迈克・罗斯在一起了
she left you for Mike Ross.
反对  纠缠证人
Objection. Badgering.
她还会说你嫉妒他的头脑
She's also gonna say that you were jealous of his mind
你这辈都在嫉妒  当你发现
your entire life, and when you found out
她离开你而和他在一起时
that she left you for him, you were as jealous
你的嫉妒达到了人类的极限
as a human being can be.
-那是真是假  -法官大人
- Now, is that true or not? - Your Honor.
让我换个说法
Let me rephrase.
是格里菲思女士会做伪证  还是你
Is Ms. Griffith going to be perjuring herself or are you?
没错  我嫉妒他
Yeah, I was jealous of him.
如果他对那件事都撒谎  还有什么能够让我们相信
And if he lied about all of that, what's to make us believe
他没有对其他事情撒谎呢
that he wasn't lying about everything else?
没有问题了  法官大人
No further questions, Your Honor.
法官大人  控诉方传唤唐娜・鲍尔森出席
Your honor, prosecution calls Donna Paulsen to the stand.
别担心  唐娜
Don't worry, Donna.
她不会直截了当地问你是否知道迈克是骗子
She won't ask you point-blank if you knew Mike was a fraud.
如果她这样问呢
What if she does?
如果你撒谎
If you lie,
他们永远不会知道
they'll never know.
鲍尔森女士  据我所知是你安排
Ms. Paulsen, it's my understanding that you arranged
斯佩克特先生的那场面试  而面试的职务目前正由
Mr. Specter's interviews for the position currently filled
迈克尔・罗斯担任
by Michael Ross.
对吗
Is that correct?
我协助了面试过程  没错
I assisted in the process, yes.
你有没有觉得罗斯先生的第一学年成绩
Did you find it suspicious that Mr. Ross
并没有列入哈佛大学班级排名中这点很可疑
wasn't listed on the Harvard class ranking from his first year?
-我没有  -为什么
- No, I didn't. - And why is that?
因为我从未被列入任何班级排名上
Because I've never been on any class ranking,
而且我现在是本市里最出色的律师秘书
and I'm the best legal secretary in the city.
哇  真是一个巧妙的回答  鲍尔森女士
Wow, that's a quippy response, Ms. Paulsen.
但是如果你如此擅长你的工作  那你怎会
But if you were so good at your job, how would you
允许一个没有出现在面试名单上的人
allow someone who wasn't even on the interview list
走进房间单独和哈维・斯佩克特待在一起
to get in a room alone with Harvey Specter?
我敢肯定你记得这张名单
I'm sure you'll recognize this list.
不管怎么样  是你打印的
After all, you typed it up.
而且看起来他的名字也没有出现在这张名单上
And it looks like his name isn't on this one either.
对  他不在名单上  但是他足够机灵
No, he wasn't on the list, but he was smart enough
仅凭几句话就进去了
to talk to his way in,
这正是一名优秀律师所做的
which is what a good lawyer does and exactly
而且也正是我要找的人
what I was looking for.
他到底说了什么就进去了
How exactly did he talk his way in?
回答问题  鲍尔森女士
Answer the question, Ms. Paulsen.
他顶替了别人的位置
He took someone else's spot.
你是指他说是他是别人
You mean he said he was someone else.
你宣过誓  鲍尔森女士
You're under oath, Ms. Paulsen.
要我提醒你作伪证会被判刑
May I remind you that perjury carries a sentence
最高五年的监禁吗
of up to five years?
他是不是说他是别人
Did he say he was someone else?
-他说他是里克・苏尔钦  -哼
- He said he was Rick Sorkin. - Ha.
所以你初见罗斯先生时  他就是个骗子
So your first introduction to Mr. Ross was as an imposter?
我没这样说
I didn't say that.
你说过他对他的名字撒谎
You said he lied about what his name was.
那他就是骗子
That makes him an imposter.
你是要撤销你的证词吗
Are you going to recant your testimony?
别看着他
Don't look at him.
不  我不撤销
No, I'm not recanting.
那就好
All right.
所以现在我们已经确定罗斯先生是个骗子
So now we've established that Mr. Ross is a liar.
那现在我们就要查明你是不是骗子
And now we're gonna find out if you're a liar.
所以  鲍尔森女士
So, Ms. Paulsen,
据你所知
To the best of your knowledge,
迈克・罗斯有没有到哈佛大学法学院上过学
did Mike Ross go to Harvard law school or not?
我要使用宪法第五修正案赋予我的权利
I'd like to assert my Fifth Amendment Right.
别不好受  鲍尔森女士
Don't feel bad, Ms. Paulsen.
我敢肯定其他人也会做相同的事情...
I'm sure others will do the same thing too...
因为...
Because...
辩护人不能提供任何证人
The defense cannot produce one person
以证明迈克・罗斯曾在哈佛法学院学习
who can place Mike Ross at Harvard Law.
我的问题问完了  法官大人
The witness could be excused, Your Honor.
我认为我们已经听够了
I think we've heard all we need to hear.
被告申请传唤吉米・柯克伍德出庭作证
Defense would like to call Jimmy Kirkwood to the stand.
反对
Objection.
他不在证人名单上
His name was not on the witness list.
反证证人
Rebuttal witness.
她刚才说我们找不到任何人证明
She just said we can't produce someone who places
迈克上过哈佛  我说我们可以
Mike at Harvard, and I say we can.
法官大人
Your Honor--
斯佩克特先生有他的权利
Mr. Specter is within his rights.
柯克伍德先生可以作证
Mr. Kirkwood can take the stand.
你怎么知道他愿意作证
How did you know he'd testify?
刚知道
I didn't until just now.
我刚认识迈克时  就在想
Well, when I first met Mike, I thought,
"这个平时从不出现
"Who is this asshole
只来参加考试的混蛋是谁啊"
"Who only ever shows up for tests?"
他是我见过最傲慢的贱人
Cockiest son of a bitch I ever saw.
但之后在吉拉德教授的课上争论一个道德问题时
But then I really got to know Mike when we were arguing
我真的认识了迈克
over an ethics question in professor Gerard's class.
一个越过界的律师
Should a lawyer who's crossed a line
应该得到第二次机会吗
be given a second chance?
我觉得不应该  但迈克意见相反
I didn't think so, but Mike did,
那时我意识到  迈克・罗斯的小指头里
and that's when I realized that Mike Ross has more integrity
存有的正直和同情心
and compassion in his little finger
比我见过的任何一个律师都多
than any other lawyer I've ever met.
如果我面临性命攸关的审判
And if I was on trial for my life,
我希望站在我身边的
There's no one I'd rather have on my side
除了我的哈佛同学迈克・罗斯外  没有别人
than my fellow Harvard alum Mike Ross.
我们说清楚些
Just so we're 100% clear,
迈克・罗斯是跟你一起上的哈佛法学院吗
was Mike Ross a student at Harvard Law School with you?
是的
Yes, he was.
没有其他问题了  法官大人
No further questions, Your Honor.
我们现在听够了
Now we've heard enough.
吉布斯女士  我给你24小时准备交叉质询
Ms. Gibbs, I'll give you 24 hours to prepare for cross.
我不需要24小时  法官大人
Oh, I don't need 24 hours, Your Honor.
柯克伍德先生  两天前
Mr. Kirkwood, isn't it true that two days ago,
罗斯先生有没有在你办公室外见你
Mr. Ross contacted you on the street outside of your Office
而你们发生了激烈的争吵
and the two of you got into a heated argument?
我有照片  你想看看吗
I have the pictures. Would you like to see them?
是这样
Yes, it's true.
那是不是几月前迈克・罗斯
And isn't it also true that Mike Ross
曾帮你婶婶获得一大笔和解金
got your aunt a large settlement several months ago,
如果他被判有罪
and if he gets convicted, it's likely
很可能那次和解会被推翻
that that settlement gets overturned?
反对  要求证人推测
Objection. Calls for speculation.
他是哈佛毕业的律师  他有能力做推测
He's a Harvard Lawyer. He's qualified to speculate.
-反对无效  -不  你说得对
- Overruled. - No, you're right.
和解可能被推翻
It'd probably get overturned,
但你要认为我说这些话是为那个
but if you think that's why I said what I said,
那你明显不了解我
then obviously you don't know me.
特雷弗・埃文斯可以因嫉妒而说谎
So Trevor Evans could lie because he's jealous,
你就不可能为婶婶而骗人吗
but you wouldn't lie for your aunt?
我不是为我婶婶说谎
I'm not lying for my aunt.
但你确实在说谎  因为说真话的人
But you are lying, because a person
绝对不会说自己在说谎
who's telling the truth wouldn't say they're lying at all.
反对  律师自行作证
Objection. Testifying.
法官大人  这位证人我问完了
You Honor, I've had enough of this witness.
他可以下庭了
He's excused.
公诉就此结束
And the prosecution rests.
唐娜
Donna.
进来
Come in.
有什么需要帮忙的吗
What can I do for you?
我其实是来见迈克的
I'm actually here to see Mike.
迈克不在
Mike's not here.
他去见哈维了
He went to go and see Harvey.
-是关于...  -关于今天的事
- Look, is this about-- - It is about today.
唐娜  我...
Donna, I--
我总是说没什么能难住我
You know, I always talk like nothing can get to me.
但今天我被难住了
Well, it did today.
我在庭上崩溃了  伤到了迈克的案子
I crumbled up there, and I hurt Mike's case.
我为自己而羞愧  而又不知道该怎么办
And I'm ashamed of myself, and I don't know what to do.
好吧
Okay.
没事  我告诉你应该做什么
Here's what you're gonna do. It's okay.
你要跟我坐下来
You are going to sit down with me
喝杯酒
and have a glass of wine
放松
and relax.
因为陪审团不傻  他们也不被允许
Because juries aren't stupid, and they aren't allowed
受你说的话影响  所以他们不会被影响
to infer anything from what you said, so they won't.
哈维  我得跟你说  我觉得我们搞定他们了
Harvey, I got to tell you, I think we got 'em.
迈克  坐下
Mike, sit down.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们今天做得不错  但还不够
We had a good day, but it wasn't enough.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
-吉米出现  -迈克
- Jimmy came through. - Mike--
我知道她打击到了他
Look, I know she landed a punch with him.
我跟你说  他还不够
And I'm telling you, he wasn't enough.
哈维  我们只需要合理怀疑就够了
Harvey, all we need is reasonable doubt.
如果我在陪审团  我不会怀疑
And if I was on that jury, I wouldn't have it.
我会认定你有罪
I'd find you guilty.
很好  那你叫我来
That's great. So you just called me over here
是要我自杀吗
to make me want to kill myself?
我叫你来是因为这案子不是怀疑的事
I called you here because this is not about doubt.
我们得给他们理由放过你
We need to give them a reason to want to let you go.
那我们要怎么办
And how exactly are we gonna do that?
做你一开始想做的事
By doing what you wanted to do in the first place.
不  现在做
No. Now?
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
那是唯一让你不上证人席
It's the only way to get you to testify
却可以作证的办法
without taking the stand.
可你说如果必要  我们会让我作证
And you said if we had to, we'd put me on the stand.
但你说对了
And you were right.
她交叉询问太厉害了
She's too good at crossing.
哈维  这是个好主意  我也希望我能做到
Well, it's a great idea, Harvey; I wish I'd had it.
但问题是  他们不会允许我
The only problem is, they're not gonna let me change
在庭审过程换律师的
my goddamn lawyer in the middle of a trial!
那我说  我们得想办法
And I'm telling you we need to figure out
让他们允许
a way to make them.
因为如果我们想不出
Because if we don't...
就会输
we're gonna lose.
你不能跟我说话的
You're not allowed to talk to me.
没错
That's true,
但如果你谁都不告诉  就没人会知道
But if you don't tell anyone, then no one's gonna know,
而我觉得你不会告诉别人的
and I don't think you're gonna want to tell anyone.
好  你想要什么
Okay. What do you want?
我得承认在你把希拉送走前
I have to admit that until you got rid of Sheila,
我真的觉得你没参与这事的
I honestly thought you weren't part of this whole thing,
但之后我做了个小调查
but then I did a little checking,
发现我可以确切指出
and I think I can pinpoint the exact day
你发现迈克・罗斯的事的日子
you found out about Mike Ross.
我要给杰西卡打电话
I'm calling Jessica.
他们让你辞职  你发现了迈克的事
They let you resign, you found out about Mike,
就借此回去做上了命名合伙人
and you used it to return as a name partner.
你知道那让我怎么看你吗
And you know what that makes me think about you?
你有头脑  可能有点卑鄙
You're resourceful, maybe a little sleazy,
但你一开始没雇那个孩子
but you didn't hire that kid in the first place.
我不会背叛我的同伴
I'm not turning on my partners.
你得通过敲诈他们得到你应得的
You had to blackmail them to get what you deserve.
那肯定让你如鲠在喉
That's got to stick in your craw.
-滚  -我会走  路易
- Go. - I will go, Louis.
但你知道我在查你时
But you know what else I found out
发现了什么吗
when I was looking into you?
你喜欢芭蕾
You like the ballet.
喜欢做泥浴
You like to go mudding.
你喜欢生活里的物质享受
You enjoy the creature comforts in life,
但监狱里可没有那些
but they don't have comforts like that in prison.
他们会输掉这场审判
They're gonna lose this trial.
你知道  我知道  他们也知道
You know it, I know it, and they know it.
你有最后一个自救的机会
You have one last chance to save yourself.
好好考虑
Think about it.
还有...
And, uh...
打电话给我
Call me.
以免太迟了
Before it's too late.
献给西蒙・保罗・马什